Guide to the New-York Historical Society Poster Collection [dates] PR 55
New-York Historical Society
- Series IX. Other Subjects, 18xx-20xx
  - Subseries IX.K. Exhibitions (Museums, Galleries, etc.)
    - "The George Washington Bridge: Photographed by Paula Barr during the Winter Solstice 1986" (Folder 09-27)
      "Printed by Rapoport; separations by Accent on Color". A note from the photographer ia attached.
    - Exhibition poster for "Walker Evans", 1987 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster copyrighted by International Museum of Photography at George Eastman House, Rochester (and exhibition held there), published by Artistworks, Landsdowne, PA., and printed at Virginia Lithograph. Image is of a 1936 Walker Evans photograph, "Roadside Stand, Vicinity - Birmingham, Alabama".
    - Exhibition poster for "Thus United Free: New Jersey in the Age of the Constitution", 1987 (Folder 09-26)
      "Poster designed bby Vincent Ciulla Design Associates, Inc.,New York, incorporating 'Washington's Reception on the Bridge at Trenton in 1789 on his Way to be Inaugurated First President of the U.S.' ...engraving on paper by Thomas Kelley...". Poster copyrighted by The New Jersey Historical Society and exhibition held there.
    - Exhibition poster for "Daniel Hauben: City Life", 1987 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster designed by Ruby Shoes Studio, and exhibition held at The Bronx Museum of the Arts with grants provided by the NEA, New York State Council on the Arts, and the Department of Cultural Affairs of the City of New York. Image: "View of 233rd Street and Broadway". Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Dec 19 1987.
    - Exhibition poster for "The Varieties of Medical Ephemera", 1987 (Folder 09-27)
      Poster designed by Jessica Helfand and Sheena Calvert. The exhibition was held at the Cushing Rotunda at Yale University School of Medicine and was from the collection of William H. Helfand. On back: Gift of Wm. Helfand and stamped Dec 22 1987.
    - Exhibition poster for "Africans in the New World 1493-1834", 1988 (Folder 09-27)
      Poster designed by Gilbert Associates. Exhibition was held at the John Carter Brown Library at Brown University and the exhibition program included two lectures by Dr. Larissa Brown and Prof. Franklin W. Knight. On back, stamped Mar 4 1988.
    - Exhibition poster for "A.J. Davis and American Classicism", 1989 (Folder 09-26)
      Exhibition presented by Historic Hudson Valley and held at Federal Hall National Memorial at corner of Wall and Nassau Streets. Image is of the Custom House (New York) and courtesy of Avery Architectural and Fine Arts Library, Columbia University.
    - Exhibition poster for "Irwin Silver", 1989 (Folder 09-27)
      Exhibition was held at the American Vision Gallery and the poster was copyrighted by the American Vision Gallery, Inc., and distributed by Bruce Teleky, Inc. The poster features a Irwin Silver photograph, "Newsstand, Brooklyn, New York, 1986".
    - Exhibition poster for "Neighbors", 1990 (Folder 09-26)
      Exhibition organized by the Smithsonian Institute Traveling Exhibition Service and the USSR Ministry of Culture in association with Seattle Organizing Committee for the 1990 Goodwill Games and Seattle Art Museum and made possible by The Boeing Company. Image is of "The Strastnoy (Holy) Boulevard" by Nisson Shifrin, 1926.
    - Exhibition poster for "Invention Spirits", 1990 (Folder 09-27)
      The poster is a reproduction of a photograph by Morris Huberland, "Shoe Shine Boys, N.Y.C. 40's". A note from the photographer explains that the photograph was first exhibited at the New-York Historical Society in 1978. The Society has several works by the photographer in its collection.
    - Exhibition poster for "The Picture of Health: Images of Medicine and Health", 1991 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster copyrighted by Philadelphia Museum of Art. Exhibition from the collection of William H. Helfand held at the Philadelphia Museum of Art and sponsored by a grant from Merck & Co., Inc., in honor of its Centennial. Images are of a Hibbard's Rheumatic Syrup and Plaster trade card, a Office Medical poster, a Dr. Dessauer's Touring Apotheke poster, and a Pastilles Valda poster.
    - Exhibition poster for "An Enduring Interest: The Photographs of Alexander Gardner", 1991 (Folder 09-26)
      Poster copyrighted by The Chrysler Museum and exhibition organized by The Chrysler Museum, Norfolk, Virginia. Image, "Abraham Lincoln, November 8, 1863" from the collection of D. Mark Katz.
    - Exhibition poster for "New York Public Library Recent Acquisitions: Photography", 1992 (Folder 09-27)
      2 copies. The poster features a silver gelatin photoprint by John Albok, "Launching (Central Park, New York, 1937)". The print is in the Photography Collection, The Miriam and Ira D. Wallach Division of Art, Prints and Photographs and is a gift of, and reproduced by permission of, Ilona Albok Vitarius. The exhibit was made possible by a generous gift of Miriam and Ira D. Wallach.
    - Series of Exhibition posters for "The Art of Persuasion", 2006 (Folder 09-27)
      The exhibition was presented by the New York Society of Etchers and held at The National Arts Club. 2 copies of the Will Barnet "Peace" poster featuring two doves. A Frances Jetter poster. A Marshall Arisman poster. An Ann Chernow poster. A Zev Deans poster.
    - Exhibition poster for "Nan Goldin, 1972-74 and The Other Side: A Slide Installation", 2007 (Folder 09-27)
      Exhibition was held at the Matthew Marks Gallery.
    - Exhibition poster for "Darren Almond", 2007 (Folder 09-27)
      Exhibition held at the Matthew Marks Gallery.
  - Subseries IX.L. Scouts
    - "Make the Next Generation Safe. Help the Boy Scouts of America.", 1917 (Folder 09-12)
      2 copies. Poster printed by Franklin Printing Co., Philadelphia. Artist: W AAP Y. Copy 1: Acquisition date (?) on back, Mar. 31, 1942.
    - "for a better Womanhood" Girl Scouts Campaign poster, 1919 (Folder 09-12)
      3 copies. Poster designed by Lestor Ralph and copyrighted in 1919 by Girl Scouts, Inc. On Copy 1, stamped on back: "E.B. Child Collection. Feb 1946". On Copy 2, stamped on front: "BCL".
    - "Boost! Boy Scout Week", ca. 1919 (Folder 09-12)
      2 copies. The image of the scout featured in the poster is by Norman Rockwell. Copy 1: Acquisition date (?) on back, Mar. 31, 1942.
    - "We Want You for Our Scoutmaster" Boy Scouts of America, ca. 1925 (Folder 09-12)
      Poster designed by Ernest Fuhr and printed by Lutz & Sheinkman, Lithographers, New York. Acquisition date (?) stamped on back, Feb 28 1925.
  - Subseries IX.M. Statue of Liberty
    - Macy's Fourth of July Fireworks advertisement, 1976 (Folder 09-23)
      Poster copyrighted by Macy's New York, and image featuring Statue of Liberty and fireworks by Griesbach-Martucci.
    - NPS Call for Comments on the planning alternatives for the Statue of Liberty and Ellis Island, 1981 (Folder 09-23)
      Poster was published by the U.S. Department of the Interior/ National Park Service with publication services provided by the graphics and editorial staffs of the Denver Service Center. Poster was sent to the Historical Society. The two-sided poster includes a fairly comprehensive list of the National Park Service's preferred plans and alternatives for its project to preserve Ellis Island and the Statue of Liberty.
    - "Keep the Torch Lit" Statue of Liberty Centennial poster, 1982 (Folder 09-23)
      Poster designed by S.L./E.I. Foundation, Inc. Poster is red and blue on a white background with the face and crown of the Statue of Liberty and "1886 CENTENNIAL 1986" featured. On back, stamped, Feb 16 1985.
    - "Statue of Liberty 1984" (Folder 09-23)
      Photograph of Statue of Liberty with scaffolding by Fred R. Tannery (Poster is also signed by Tannery). Copyright by Eye of a Camera Production and published bby Harbert Corporation, NYC. On back, stamped, Jan 12 1985.
    - "Lady of Liberty: A Proud Heritage", 1986 (Folder 09-23)
      Poster published by Federated-Fry Metals, Altoona, Pennsylvania, from an oil painting by George Plataz in 1986.
  - Subseries IX.N. 9/11 (incl posters by Creative Time)
    - "Faces of Ground Zero -- Giant Polaroid Collection", c. 2001 (Folder 09-20)
      3 copies. Poster created and signed by Joe McNally Photography. In note at bottom - the reproduced images were created by only life-sized Polaroid camera.
    - "September 11th", 2001 (Folder 09-20)
      Giclee print poster (3/6) created by Erica Hart in 2001. Includes images of hands, rubble, fire, and the statue of Liberty. On back, "Gift of Mrs. Erica Hart, 2002".
    - "Don't Tread on Me", 2001 (Folder 09-20)
      Poster created and signed by Boyd G. Sharp. Images include twin towers, bald eaagle, American flag, Liberty torch, and firefighter. On back, "Gift 2014".
    - "Firefighters Angel. The Bravest of the Brave. Thank You for the Lives You Save.", 2001 (Folder 09-20)
      The poster was created by ArtAid. It includes the names of the firefighters who died on 9.11.01. The image is the Firefighters Angel.
    - "Fifth Avenue ... September 2001" (Folder 09-20)
      Poster was created and signed by Libby Lesher with contributions going to United Firefighters Association. The images are of buildings along Fifth Avenue in Manhattan flying American flags.
    - "WTC 1976-2001" (Folder 09-20)
      Poster created by Sandy Walker after an ink drawing, "World Trade Center" 1980 by Sandy Walker. An accompanying note from the artist explains the gift of the posters in relation to the WTC show organnized by The New-York Historical Society.
    - "World Trade Center 2001. One Nation, Indivisible." (Folder 09-20)
      Poster created by Everen T. Brown. Photographic image of Manhattan from the top of the World Trade Tower with an American flag.
    - "We Will Always Remember Where We Were And How We Felt - We Shall Never Forget How We Feel.", 2001 (Folder 09-20)
      Poster created and signed by Michael Joseph. Poster includes image of the World Trade Center with a Cross between the towers and a raised impression of the Manhattan skyline with the World Trade Center.
    - "Ground Zero 9/11/01", 2001 (Folder 09-20)
      3 copies. Poster is a reprint of a painting of fifefighters at Ground Zero helping an injured person. The painting and the poster are both signed by the artist, Maurice Scherer (?). On back of each copy, "Unsolicited gift, 2015".
    - "Graphics of New York City before September 11, 2001" (Folder 09-20)
      Poster and collection created by Jimmy DiResta, "over 100 images and growing". Poster includes several images of business logos using Manhattan skyline with the World Trade Center. On back, "Unsolicited gift, 2015".
    - White poster sheet with twin towers cut out, c.2001 (Folder 09-21)
      2 copies. Poster created by Hans Haacke for CreativeTime.
    - Advertisement for town meeting, "Listening to the City. Remember and Rebuild", 2002 (Folder 09-20)
      The town meeting was held on July 20, 2002, at the Jacob Javits Center, and was sponsored by the Civic Alliance, convened by Regional Planning Association, to Rebuild Downtown New York.The New-York Historical Society poster features images of Downtown New York from 1664 through 2001.
    - "De-Fuse The Minefield of Anger", 2002 (Folder 09-21)
      Poster by the ANTI.BIAS. Squad, students from East Side Community High School, NYC. Sponsored by Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Creative Time, Poets & Writers, Van Alen Institute, and Worldstudio Foundation invited poster submissions for this exhibition, Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Accompanying poster is a small pamphlet on the exhibition.
    - "Life/Death" remote control, 2002 (Folder 09-21)
      Poster by Nebojsa Seric Shoba, artist. Sponsored by Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Creative Time, Poets & Writers, Van Alen Institute, and Worldstudio Foundation invited poster submissions for this exhibition, Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Accompanying poster is a small pamphlet on the exhibition.
    - "Contribute a Memory", 2002 (Folder 09-21)
      Poster by Eric Lifton, architect. "More memories at www.randomaccessmemorial.org." Sponsored by Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Creative Time, Poets & Writers, Van Alen Institute, and Worldstudio Foundation invited poster submissions for this exhibition, Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Accompanying poster is a small pamphlet on the exhibition.
    - "How The Lurking...", 2002 (Folder 09-21)
      Poster and poem by Elena Alexander, November 2001. Sponsored by Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Creative Time, Poets & Writers, Van Alen Institute, and Worldstudio Foundation invited poster submissions for this exhibition, Time to Consider: The Arts Respond to 9.11. Accompanying poster is a small pamphlet on the exhibition.
    - The Twin Towers Logo Project 2001-2006 (Folder 09-21)
      Poster created by Phyllis Wrynn, photographs and art direction byb Phyllis Wrynn, assisted by Eric March, and published by Park Slope Gallery. Poster features logos with the twin towers. On accompanying note, "Gift of Linda Ferber, 2019".
  - Subseries IX.O. History Responds collecting: Covid-19 / Social & Racial Justice
    - "Yellow Peril Supports Black Power", 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      InkJet Print by Kenn Lam. History Responds Collections Initiative. Gift of the artist, Kenn Lam, 2021.
    - "Apocalyptic Self Care", 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      Poster by Emma Sasso. History Responds Collections Initiative. Gift of the artist, Emma Sasso, 2021.
    - "No One Is Above The Law (side 1); Stop The GOP Coup (side 2), 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      History Responds Collections Initiative.
    - "No racism. No fear. Immigrants are welcome here.", 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      Poster by United Against Racism and Fascism, NYC. History Responds Collections Initiative.
    - "Black Lives Matter", 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      Black Lives Matter superimposed on sheet with Asian Characters. History Responds Collections Initiative.
    - "New York Tough", 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      Poster capturing early days of Covid19 in New York with timeline and phases. [Signed?] "Excelsior! Andrew Cuomo". History Responds Collections Initiative.
    - "Black Lives Matter. Download this poster for FREE at: tinyurl.com/ybqvtogn", 2020 (Folder OSFF-09-29)
      Includes names of many whose lives were lost. History Responds Collections Initiative.
  - Subseries IX.P. New York Buildings and Views
    - The Architectural League of New York's Beaux Arts Tour, 1975 (Folder 09-28)
      Featured photograph of the U.S. Customs House Interior by Cervin Robinson. Tour details on backside of poster. Gift of Deborah Nevins.
    - "Grand Central Terminal", [1980's] (Folder 09-28)
      Poster designed by Metro-North Commuter Railroad and features architectural plans and details of the terminal.
    - The Style of Long Island: 300 Years of Architecture and the Decorative Arts, 1987 (Folder 09-28)
      Poster designed by Joseph del Gaudio Design Group Inc. The chart featuring 117 images of architecture and decorative arts was compiled bby Carolyn Max and Deborah C. Lee with the assistance of others and published by The Society for the Preservation of Long Island Antiquities, as a memorial to their late trustee, Bertha Benkard Rose. On back, in pencil, "Gift of Jean Ashton, July 1987."
    - "Wanted: A Waterfront for New York", 1987 (Folder 09-28)
      Poster designed by Anthony Russell, Inc. and photograph of the lower westside of Manhattan's waterfront by Jake Rajs. Poster explains the Idea Competition by the Municipal Art Society for a four mile stretch of waterfront on Manhattan's lower westside.
    - "Fifth Avenue" poster, 1988 (Folder 09-28)
      Poster copyrighted by Laurel Arts, Los Angeles; photography by David Yost; Electronic Prepress Response System: Scitex America Corp, Gayle Rosen; printed by Acme Printing Company, Wilmington, MA; accompanying booklet by Steve Marvin. Poster features photographs of the "majestic facade of Fifth Avenue facing Central Park."
    - "Manhattan Municipal Building Seventy-fifth Anniversary, 1914-1989" (Folder 09-28)
      Poster designed by CityGraphics. Artwork courtesy of New-York Historical Society. Poster features a reproduction of original ink and watercolor of Municipal Building, c. 1908.
    - "New York City" by Steven Hans Lindner, 2001 (Folder 09-28)
      Aerial view of Manhattan, foreground; Bronx, Brooklyn, Queens, background. Copyright by Steven Hans Lindner, 2001.
    - Series of 4 "Rebuild Penn Station" posters, 2017 (Folder 09-28)
      "The Station We Deserve" features image of Rebuilt Seventh Avenue Facade by Jeff Stikeman Architectural Art. "Civilized Arrivals" features image of Rebuilt Concourse with Widened Platforms and Tripled Escalators by Jeff Stikeman Architectural Art. "Spaces to Inspire" features image of Rebuilt Main Waiting Room by Jeff Stikeman Architectural Art. "Reasons to Linger." features image of New Covered Arcades on 31st and 33rd Streets by Jeff Stikeman Architectural Art. Sponsors for all posters include the National Civic Art Society, Remains Lighting, Barn Farm Studio, and Atelier & Co. Posters were a gift of Sam Turvey of Rebuild Penn Station, National Civic Art Society.
  - Subseries IX.Q. Transportation / Airlines (incl TWA)
    - "2 Days to Europe", 1936 (Folder OSFF-09-33)
      Poster designed by Jupp Wiertz for the Hamburg-American Line-North German Lloyd, General Passenger Agents. Poster features a Hindenburg Zeppelin flying over the Manhattan skyline, specifically over the Empire State Building.
    - "TWA - Service Aerien Rayonnant Sur L'Amerique", ca. 1952 (Folder OSFF-09-33)
      Trans World Airline poster lithographed in U.S.A.
    - "TWA...Save...Fly to America...Sky Tourist Service", ca. 1952 (Folder OSFF-09-33)
      Trans World Airlines poster litho in U.S.A.
    - "Fly TWA New York", 1956 (Folder OSFF-09-33)
      TWA poster designed by David Klein. This poster features a night skyline.
    - "New York...Fly TWA", ca. 1960 (Folder OSFF-09-33)
      Poster designed and signed by David Klein. TWA New York poster features many New York City landmarks, including the Statue of Liberty, St. Patricks, Columbus Circle column. Poster was "Litho in U.S.A."
  - Subseries IX.R. United Nations
    - "The United Nations for Peace and World Progress", 1946 (Folder OSFF-09-34)
      The poster was printed by the Government Printing Office and was a Department of State publication. The poster features a diagram of the United Nations corporate structure and gives examples of how the United Nations promotes international cooperation. Acquisition date (?) on back, Oct. 31, 1946.
    - "We, the Peoples of the United Nations, have determined...", 1946 (Folder OSFF-09-34)
      The poster was based on the preamble to the United Nations' charter and was published and distributed as a public service by General Mills. On back, the complete preamble is set out. Acquisition date (?) on back, Oct. 31, 1946.
  - Subseries IX.S. Lesbian/Gay/Bisexual/Transgender/Queer (LGBTQ+)
    - Keith Haring - Ignorance=Fear/Silence=Death, 1989 (Folder OSFF-09-31)
      Poster by Keith Haring for Act Up to fight AIDS.
    - "Unfortunately, History Has Set The Record A Little Too Straight.", 1989 (Folder OSFF-09-31)
      Poster designed by Laurie Casagrande. Poster (#P231CW A Little Too Straight) part of "Tools For Change" from Syracuse Cultural Workers (SCW). In support of National Coming Out Day -- poster features images of 10 figures who made their mark on history, regardless of their sexual orientation.
    - "Joan Jett-Blakk For President...By Any Means Necessary", [1992] (Folder OSFF-09-31)
      Published by Imprime:BOCM. Image of Joan Jett-Blakk by Marc Geller. Signed by Joan Jett-Blakk.
    - "Vote on November 7th...come out and into the voting booth" Those Who Have Fallen poster, 2000 (Folder OSFF-09-31)
      Poster published by Gill Operating Foundation to support www.outvote2000.org.
    - "Vote on November 7th...come out and into the voting booth" Make Sure They Know We're Out Here poster, 2000 (Folder OSFF-09-31)
    - "Lesbian Pride", undated (Folder OSFF-09-31)
      No publisher or designer given. Image is of two nudes hugging. Poster is in two colors: purple and orange.